# Chanchal Prajapati

[USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER]

I'm a user experience designer. I uncover insights, curate design-led business strategies & design empathic experiences. I'm passionate about humanising technology & making it accessible - one experience at a time.

In my latest work experience at Samsung, I have worked across Samsung's diverse portfolio - SmartPhones, Home Appliances, Smartwatches and new product innovations. With the expertise to deeply understand the socio-cultural / economic / political landscape of consumer markets, I have led global research and projects to create locally inspired global consumer experiences.

E-main: chanchalprajapati95@gmail.com Phone: +91 9718867845



# EDUCATION

2017-2020
 Master of Design - Interaction Design
 NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF DESIGN, BANGALORE

2013-2017

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science

IIIT DELHI

### EXPERIENCE

LEAD UX DESIGNER - SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS

(MAR 2023 - PRESENT)

Working at Samsung Design Delhi with the CX Strategy Team | UX Innovation Group

UX DESIGNER - SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS

(JAN 2020 - MAR 2023)

Working at Samsung Design Delhi with the UX Design

Team | UX Innovation Group

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN INTERN

(JUNE 2019 - DEC 2019)

Working with the 'Research in Automation & Digitisation' (RDA) unit, in the domain of autonomous

systems

http://chanchalprajapati.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chanchalprajapati

https://behance.net/chanch95

https://github.com/Chanch95

#### PUBLICATION

HACKATHON | MARCH 2019
 Second Prize | Game Design Hackathon
 Gameskraft and Interaction Design Foundation

RESEARCH PAPER | APRIL 2018
 Evaluating Ease of Interaction with Voice Assistants
 SIDeR (Student interaction Design Research
 Conference, 2018)

## SKILLS

Design Strategy

Mentorship & Training

Design Research & Validation

Project Management

Ethnographic ResearchUsability StudySystem DesignStakeholder CommunicationNew Research FrameworksProduct Design Proposal Pitches

Service Design

New Product Incubation

Interaction Design Design-Led Strategy Presentations

Sprints & Rapid Prototyping Vendor Management

Co-Creation With Leadership

Executive Presentations

# TOOLS & TECHNICAL SKILLS

Figma Arduino

Sketch Processing (P5.js)

Adobe Suite C#
HTML/CSS/Tailwind C

Unity 3D R Studio
After Effects Java